# **SIRUI ZHU**

Portfolio available at : siruizhu.github.io

## **SELECTED PROJECTS**

## China's Long March to space

https://graphics.reuters.com/SPACE-EXPLORATION-MOON/0100B0BH0NZ/ind ex.html Researching China space program and processing data. Using After effects for animations, Illustrator for rockets illustrations. Ai2html and responsive web design. .

## Apple products made in China could face tariffs by year's end

https://graphics.reuters.com/USA-TRADE-APPLE/0100B25R11Y/index.html Collaborate with a colleague. Data processing and research. Icons illustrations and interactive scrollytelling.

#### Treasure of architecture: China to better protect architecture relics

https://siruizhu.github.io/cultural--relics/ API to access the data. Interactive graphics showing all cultural relics names, classifications and distribution.

## The past 50 years of refugees crisis

https://siruizhu.github.io/refugee project/ Exploration of 50 years refugees dataset. Python(pandas) for data cleaning and analysis, visualization using D3. Scrollytelling with interactive charts.

## Hollywood Age Gap: A Visual Exploration of Age and On-Screen Romance

https://malbasi.github.io/hollywood-age-gap/ Group project: Analyse the hollywood movies age gap. Visualization using D3. Scrollytelling with interactive charts.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Lede Program for Data Journalism, Columbia University

May 2018 - Dec. 2018 New York, USA (Obtained \$16,000 Scholarship)

Courses: Python, data analysis with pandas, matplotlib, SQL, JavaScript, D3.js, basic machine learning (regression and prediction) and text analysis, web app development, geographic analysis with QGIS, Scrollytelling.

## M.A., Broadcast Journalism, University of Sheffield

Sept. 2014 - Sept. 2015 Sheffield, UK

Portfolio: London's Chinatown Feels the Squeeze of Rent Rises (video)

## B.A., Broadcasting and Compering, Wuhan University

Sept. 2010 - June 2014 Wuhan, China

Dissertation: Analysis of China Reality Show from the Perspective of Communication.

## **VOLUNTEER WORK**

Sheffield Student Union Charity Hitchhike Mar. 2015 Wuhan Green NGO Oct. 2011 340 W 86<sup>th</sup> st # 6A New York, 10024 (646) 9449596 surizhu9@gmail.com

#### **PROFESSIONAL SKILLS**

Data: Python, pandas, matplotlib, SQL, APIs,

Selenium, BeautifulSoup

Web: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, D3.js Mapping: Leaflet, QGIS, Mapbox Services: Github, Travis, Heroku Applications: Adobe Illustrator,

Photoshop, After Effects, Adobe Premiere, Final

Cut Pro, Edius

**Language:** Mandarin(Native) English(Professional)

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## <u>Thomson Reuters</u> | New York, USA Data Visualization Developer intern April 1st 2019 to present

Designing and developing interactive & static graphics for daily news and special reports.

## Wuhan Dyclub Data Technology Lit.Co. | Wuhan, China

Training Supervisor Nov. 2016 - May 2018
Organized more than twenty Dyclub data
journalism online trainings. Managed and wrote

"Weekly Data Journalism." Operated visualization tool *Dydata.io*, executed data analysis on users. Organized "Third Data Journalism Competition" and award ceremony.

## Hubei Televisions | Wuhan, China

*TV Producer* Mar 2016 - Oct. 2016 Produced children's reality show and wrote children's show script.

## UK Chinese Times | London, UK

**News Editor intern** June 2015 - July 2015 Edited international news pieces

## China National Radio | Beijing

*News Editor intern* Feb. 2013 - May 2013 Edited radio news, work on 2013 NPC and CPPCC reporting for two weeks.

#### **AWARDS**

Excellent Journalist of Wuhan University *June* 2011

Excellent Student for University Article Writing Competition for Celebrating Xinhai Revolution 100th Anniversary Oct. 2011